Guide to the Leonard I. Schiff Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Leonard I. Schiff papers
1948-1971
SC0220
Schiff, Leonard I. (Leonard Isaac), 1915-
26 Linear feet
Professional correspondence, reports and committee papers relating to Professor Schiff's work at Stanford as well as with the National Academy of Science and NASA. Of note are papers relating to his term as head of the Physics Department at Stanford 1948-66 and as a faculty leader. Also includes mimeographed version of his textbook on quantum mechanics, 1947.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Leonard Schiff, 1979.
Information about Access
none
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of physics at Stanford University, 1947-1970; head of the Physics Department 1948-1966.
Description of the Collection
Professional correspondence, reports and committee papers relating to Professor Schiff's work at Stanford as well as with the National Academy of Science and NASA. Of note are papers relating to his term as head of the Physics Department at Stanford 1948-66 and as a faculty leader. Also includes mimeographed version of his textbook on quantum mechanics, 1947.
Access Terms
Alfred P. Sloan Foundation.; Barschall, H. H. (Heinrich Hermann), 1915-; Bloch, Felix, 1905-; Drell, Sidney D., (Sidney David), 1926-; Hofstadter, Robert, 1915-1990; Kaplan, Henry S., 1918-1984; Schawlow, Arthur L., 1921-1999; Schiff, Leonard I. (Leonard Isaac), 1915-; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; United States. Air Force.; College teachers.; Nuclear physics --Research.; Physicists.; Physics.; Quantum theory.; Relativity (Physics); Reports.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1987-031
  - Experimental Towing Tank, E. T. T., Stevens Institute of Technology (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Super conducting gyroscope (original mss), 1959, and Proposed Experimental Test of General Relativity (proposal letter), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Relativity and gyroscope experiment (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gyro experiment after 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Technical papers, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Technical papers, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Technical papers, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Technical papers, 1960s-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Schiff, Notes on Quantum Mechanics (bound volume of mss notes), 1943-44 (Box 2)
  - Physics 340, Autumn 1970/71 (1) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Physics 340, Autumn 1970/71 (2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Physics 340, Autumn 1970/71 (3) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Quantum physics course evaluations (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Quantum physics class file, part 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Quantum physics class file, part 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dept. of Physics, Annual Report, Oct 1, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1947-58 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Electric Microwave Lab, 1956-62 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journal of Mathematical Physics, correspondence re, 1957-71 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ladera (Peninsula Housing Association) Board, 1948-49 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lectures, non-technical, 1958-69 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Members of the Corporation Visiting Committee, MIT, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nobel Prize nomination forms, 1950-57 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Vernon J. Pick (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - L. I. Schiff, biographical and bibliographical (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - L. I. Schiff, memorials (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Space Science Board and Committee (NAS) 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tata Institute of Fundamental Research (Bombay) 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Varian Associates, miscellany, 1949-64 (Box 3, Folder 14)